creditsafe.com 2017-12-19

# Creditsafe Privacy Notice

### This notice is to articulate how Creditsafe collects and processes personal data. We are committed to providing a transparent approach regarding the collection, processing and on-going management of personal data, 

### How we use your information

This privacy notice is to inform you of how Creditsafe collects personal information and covers:-

  * Our customers who use our services
  * Visitors to our websites 
  * Data held within our on-line products
  * People who are making an enquiry or complaint

### Visitors to our Website

When someone visits www.creditsafe.com we collect standard internet log information and details of visitor behavior patterns. We do this to find out things such as the number of visitors to the various parts of the site. We also use piece of java script code to implement a reverse IP address tracking function. This technology identifies businesses visiting our site and the pages that are being used. This helps us analyze data about web page traffic in order to develop and improve our website. This technology does not track personal data, it stores the IP addresses visiting our website and the pages that were visited. This does not include any additional cookies on the website.

We collect this information in a way which does not identify anyone. We do not make any attempt to find out the identities of those visiting our website. We will not associate any data gathered from this site with any personally identifying information from any source.  If we do want to collect personally identifiable information through our website, we will make this clear as we do to our subscription customers who access our services via our website. We will always make it clear when we collect personal information and will explain what we intend to do with it. 

### Use of Cookies 

Cookies are small files stored on your computer. Typically, they're used by websites to do things like maintain your preferences, identify your session, store items in shopping carts and for storing authentication status. These files cannot harm your computer, but they can potentially be used to track some of your browser activity, and in the hands of hackers, can give away some personal data. To find out further information on cookies and how you can deal with them effectively click here.

In order to understand user activity on our website we use Google Analytics to understand the number of visitors on the site, which pages are being viewed and if users came via a third party site.

Cookies used are:

We use one cookie ASP.NET_Session Id for user session. The rest of cookies are created by by Google scripts (google translate and google maps): _ga PREF PREF SNID OGP OGPC SID HSID SSID APISID SAPISID NID _dc_gtm_UA-43018132-1 _dc_gtm_UA-69095444-1

Site: app.creditsafeuk.com

**Name of Cookie**

| 

**Type of Cookie**

| 

**Expiry Period**

| 

**Reason for Cookie**

| 

**Description**  
  
---|---|---|---|---  
ASP.NET_SessionId | Session Cookie | Session | 

Your visit

| Tracks your session on server.  
Password | Session Cookie | Session | 

Your visit

| Used in auto login for your browser session.  
RememberME | Session Cookie | Session | 

Your visit

| Used in auto login for your browser session.  
RememberMyPassword | Session Cookie | Session | 

Your visit

| Used in auto login for your browser session.  
Username | Session Cookie | Session | 

Your visit

| Used in auto login for your browser session.  
Headerbar | Session Cookie | Session | 

Your visit

| Maintains visual state of sidebar/accordion across session.  
  
Site: www2.creditsafeuk.com

Name of Cookie | Type of Cookie | Expiry Period | Reason for Cookie | 

Description  
  
---|---|---|---|---  
headerbar | Session Cookie | Session | Your visit | Maintains visual state of sidebar/accordion across session.  
__utma | Persistent Cookie | 2 years | Analytics | This cookie is set by Google Analytics and is used to improve our understanding of how people use our website and services.  
__utmb | Persistent Cookie | 30 minutes | Analytics | This cookie is set by Google Analytics and is used to improve our understanding of how people use our website and services.  
__utmc | Session Cookie | Session | Analytics | This cookie is set by Google Analytics and is used to improve our understanding of how people use our website and services.  
__utmz | Persistent Cookie | 30 minutes | Analytics | This cookie is set by Google Analytics and is used to improve our understanding of how people use our website and services.  
machine-id | Persistent Cookie | Never | Analytics | 

This Cookie is set by Open Tracker and is used to improve our understanding of how people user our website and service.  
  
Google Remarketing | Persistent Cookie | Never | Advertising | 

This Cookie is set by Google and used for remarketing purposes. This cookie will be come into effect when you have visited the [www.creditsafeuk.com](http://www.creditsafeuk.com/) website and will activate when viewing third party websites through Google’s Adsense advertising channel. You can opt out of this by visiting Google’s [Ad Preferences Manager](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/?sig=ACi0TCjM8FK7kdZ1TmqdPm8nPSU6fhKttTpJd5w-c5KslXbab8z25XxfGibxwXV-FzXzaqJhGRI7TXfmREWAFwj4L6k9hK73BvX6gnf7BTDXWzTBjUyWYufZo63wQJugCHUSB_T04M3NEKVgL7n2-SERbLWGynkLs6wnIuTG94mKyVGJmL4Q3Ogc7-dvYjsgcZdyjItDEhoq&hl=en).  
  
Target360 | Persistent Cookie | Never | Advertising | 

Target360 – These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.  
  
Site: creditsafeuk.typepad.com

Name of Cookie | Type of Cookie | Expiry Period | Reason for Cookie | Description  
---|---|---|---|---  
__utma | Persistent Cookie | 2 years | Analytics | This cookie is set by Google Analytics and is used to improve our understanding of how people use our website and services.  
__utmz | Persistent Cookie | 30 minutes | Analytics | This cookie is set by Google Analytics and is used to improve our understanding of how people use our website and services.  
  
These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. [Click here for an overview of privacy at Google](https://privacy.google.com/).

### People who complete a contact form

The Creditsafe website uses a number of “Contact us” forms allowing visitors to supply us with their details so we may get in touch with them to discuss our products and services. The details on these forms are collected and passed to our customer service teams to allow them to contact the person completing them.

### People whose information is contained within our products

Creditsafe’s products contain information on the identification, analysis and creditworthiness of businesses. That information is sourced from many original suppliers such as Companies House and the Registry Trust. This data is displayed within Company Credit Reports which can be accessed by our subscription customers when they have logged into our secure services using their user name and password. The information held in our reports may include information that can be used to identify individuals such as company directors. This information will have been sourced by Creditsafe from the original data collector who will have explained what data was being collected and how and why it might be used by third parties such as Creditsafe. Typically this might include directors’ details filed at Companies House as part of a company’s annual return.

### People who email us

Creditsafe uses email as one of the primary sources of communication with customers and this may be monitored and used by us for reasons of security and for monitoring compliance within the company. Email monitoring or blocking software may also be used to protect personal and other sensitive data within Creditsafe. Please be aware that you have a responsibility to ensure that any email you send to us is within the bounds of the law.

### People who make a complaint to us

When we receive a complaint from a person we make up a file containing the details of the complaint. This normally contains the identity of the complainant, contact details and any other details of the complaint. We will only use the personal information we collect to process the complaint and to check on the level of service we provide.

### Complaints or queries

We take the collection and processing of personal data very seriously and encourage individuals and/or organizations to bring to our attention any aspects of our operations that they feel collects or processes personal data in an unfair, misleading or inappropriate way.  This notice is written to give clarity and ensure our key processing activities are clear and understood. It does not provide all aspects of processing and use of personal data but you are welcome to request further information if required.  
For any complaints, queries of requests for information please contact us at   
[USPAInfo@creditsafe.com ](mailto:USPAInfo@creditsafe.com) or call **(855)551-6903**. 

### Job Applicants, current and previous

When individuals apply to work at Creditsafe we will only use the information they supply to us to process their application. Where we want to disclose information to a third party, for example where we want to take up a reference or obtain a criminal records check we will not do so without informing them beforehand. Personal information about unsuccessful candidates will be held for 12 months after the recruitment exercise has been completed, it will then be destroyed or deleted.

Once a person has taken up employment with Creditsafe, we compile a personnel file relating to their employment. The information contained in this will be kept secure and will only be used for purposes directly relevant to that person’s employment and fulfillment of business requirements. Once their employment has ended we will retain the file in accordance with the requirements of our retention schedule, which is 7 years and then dispose or delete it.

### Access to personal information

We are committed to providing people access to their personal information. Any individual who would like to know whether personal information is held on them by Creditsafe can make a Subject Access Request (SAR). If we do hold information about you we will:

  * Give you a description of it;
  * Tell you why we are holding it;
  * Tell you who it could be disclosed to; and
  * Let you have a copy of the information in an intelligible form.

If you wish to make a request for any personal information we may hold please contact us in writing, addressing it to the Group Information Security Manager, address details are provided below.

If we do hold information about you, you can ask us to correct any mistakes by, once again, contacting the Group Information Security Manager.

### Links to other websites

This privacy notice does not cover the links within this site linking to other websites. We encourage you to read the privacy statements on the other websites you visit.

### How to contact us

If you want to request information about our privacy policy you can email us or write to:

Creditsafe USA   
1550 Pond Road Suite 100  
Allentown   
PA 18104

Website: www.creditsafe.com
